<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Authors on ENDOMIC Team</title>
    <link>/authors/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Authors on ENDOMIC Team</description>
    <generator>Source Themes academia (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Copyright &amp;copy; {year}</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 15 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	    <atom:link href="/authors/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/authors/adan/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/authors/adan/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I am a &lt;a href=&#34;https://pro.univ-lille.fr/adan-jose-garcia/&#34;&gt;Research Fellow in Digital Health&lt;/a&gt; at the Department of Computer Science, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.cristal.univ-lille.fr/&#34;&gt;CRIStAL Lab&lt;/a&gt;, University of Lille, France. This is a collaborative project with the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.chu-lille.fr/&#34;&gt;Lille University Hospital&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://include-project.chru-lille.fr/home-project/&#34;&gt;INCLUDE&lt;/a&gt;. My current project involves developing and applying unsupervised machine learning techniques to classify patients with systemic autoimmune diseases.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before joining the University of Lille, I was a &lt;a href=&#34;http://emps.exeter.ac.uk/computer-science/staff/aj504&#34;&gt;Research Fellow in Machine Learning&lt;/a&gt; at the Department of Computer Science, Institute of Data Science and Artificial Intelligence, University of Exeter, United Kingdom (UK). Before this, I was a Postdoctoral Researcher with the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.alliancembs.manchester.ac.uk/research/decision-science/&#34;&gt;Decision and Cognitive Sciences Research Centre&lt;/a&gt;, University of Manchester, UK. I hold M.Sc. and Ph.D. degrees in Computer Science from the Center for Research and Advanced Studies of the National Polytechnic Institute, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.cinvestav.mx/&#34;&gt;Cinvestav-IPN&lt;/a&gt;, Mexico.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In general, my scientific expertise is focused on investigating cluster analysis methods, also known as unsupervised machine learning, in the area of Artificial Intelligence. My research consists in creating and adapting clustering approaches (e.g., multi-view clustering, biclustering) and their applications to different research fields such as digital healthcare, labour market and network analysis. In these scenarios, the clustering problem is modelled as a numerical or combinatorial optimisation problem, where I have mainly focused on using nature-based metaheuristics (e.g. evolutionary algorithms). In addition, I have studied the problem of automatically determining the number of clusters inherent in the input data and the statistical validation of the resulting clusters. My research currently focuses on developing integrative cluster analysis approaches to address healthcare-related data problems and help to understand better disease complications and treatment goals.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/authors/vincent/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/authors/vincent/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;heading&#34;&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am a &lt;a href=&#34;https://pro.univ-lille.fr/vincent-sobanski/&#34;&gt;Professor in Internal Medicine&lt;/a&gt; at the University of Lille and CHU Lille; my research work aims to better characterize the clinical heterogeneity of systemic autoimmune diseases and to understand the role of autoantibodies. As clinical physicians, we are constantly looking for the best tools to diagnose, search for complications or predict prognosis in order to decide on therapeutic management. We already use patient stratification methods for the diseases we are in charge of; new technological tools provide new avenues for research. I have been strongly involved in this theme in the hospital and university community. My academic work is focused on helping to diagnose and stratify patients through new technologies and an integrated approach, building on and developing my own research on rare diseases (autoimmune and fibrotic pathologies), but with a strong commitment to disseminate and use these skills for the entire community.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Alexandre FILIOT</title>
      <link>/authors/alexandre-filiot/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/authors/alexandre-filiot/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Clarisse DHAENENS</title>
      <link>/authors/clarisse-dhaenens/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/authors/clarisse-dhaenens/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>David LAUNAY</title>
      <link>/authors/david-launay/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/authors/david-launay/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Julia HANDL</title>
      <link>/authors/julia-handl/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/authors/julia-handl/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Julie JACQUES</title>
      <link>/authors/julie-jacques/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/authors/julie-jacques/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/authors/admin/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/authors/admin/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;ENDOtyper les Maladies Inflammatoires Chroniques&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Robert Ford</title>
      <link>/authors/robert-ford/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/authors/robert-ford/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/authors/aurelien/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/authors/aurelien/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;heading&#34;&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Description goes here&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/authors/louisa/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/authors/louisa/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;heading&#34;&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Description goes here&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/authors/solange/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/authors/solange/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;heading&#34;&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Description goes here&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
